

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





# Vijayendrs S Pothubari () Featured

A Cloud Solutions Architect, DevOps Automation & Kubernetes Consultant. M.Tech in



Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computers]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Designation: Principal ServiceOps Consultant - II

Current Company: Planful Inc,

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

ivanilenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: aws,kunbernetes,terraform,liferay,docker,devops,Apache Tomcat,Web

Server, Websphere, Mongo DB, Postgresql, NoSQL, Cloud Security

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills

#### **Summary**

Post Graduation from IIIT.

 $11\ years\ of\ experience\ in\ Cloud\ networking,\ Mddleware\ DevOps\ administration\ \&\ Data\ Science\ algorithms.$ 

Transforming raw data to conform to assumptions of the ML algorithm.

Have Extensive experience in Design, Implementation, and Production support for Kubernetes Clusters with Docker hosts over 200 Containers and Pods. with several different products.

## **Work Experience**

Planful Inc, as Principal ServiceOps Consultant - II Jun 2018 to Till Date

\*Infrastructure migration methodologies, including mass application movements into the cloud in large, heavily regulated enterprise environments & to ensure better business continuity by migrating the on-premise environments to AWS doubt

\*VMware ESX Installation, Configuration & Administration.

.Led Kubernetes design, implementation & architectural team.

#### Nirvana Logic Inc as MIDDLEWARE DEVOPS ENGINEER Oct 2016 to Mar 2018

- \* Start-up: A tech company, offering services towards making spiritual growth and networking more accessible.)
- \* Product: SPIRITUAL WELLNESS
- \* Clients: Mllennium Trust Portal Foundation & Strategy, US Enterprise Digital Experience portal features Case study
- \* Technologies: Liferay-DXP, Tomcat8, JDK8, Nginx, PostgreSQL9.4, MYSQLv5, MSAD, Amazon Web Services, Mware6.0, WordPress, Docker, Jenkins Chef, GIT, Nexus, ELK stack Roles: Application Infra Architect, DevOps Engineer.
- Operations: Provisioning, maintaining and improving upon server infrastructure, split between physical data centres and AWS.
- \* Designs, implements, and supports cloud-based infrastructure for 'Nirvanalogic' applications.
- \* Directed software design and development across 10-member development team while remaining focused on meeting client needs for functionality, timeline and performance.
- \* Automated and implemented backup and recovery procedures for Containerization & orchestration system that resulted in zero down time.
- \* Implemented new software applications and operating system rollouts across business enterprise, including Jenkins, Kubernetes and WordPress.
- \* Reached working prototype stage of development quickly due to insight into user needs and requirements.
- \* Worked closely with other business analysts, development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver high availability solutions for mission-critical applications.
- \* Drove project lifespan from concept to final rollout in continuous integration and development, system deployment, testing and monitoring for Portal technology & Day Ope methodology

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. testing and monitoring for notice technology & Devops methodology.

- \* Provided updated patches for operating systems and system configuration to improve efficiency by 40%.
- \* Provided 24/7 support for web- and client-based applications, file and data feeds and batch processes to prevent impact to business.
- Involved in all testing procedures and wrote test cases and scenarios for development team.
- \* Updated department documentation such as license databases, infrastructure maps and FAQs to maintain consistent response levels.
- Utilized such technologies as ASP.NET, M/C, HTML5, JavaScript and SQL Server 2012 to develop new applications.
- \* Interfaced with customers and developers to diagnose problems and implement configuration requirements and solutions.
- Participated in on-site requirements gathering sessions and translated dient requirements to determine project scope.

# Kelton Tech Solutions Ltd, as SR. WEBSPHERE ANALYST

Mar 2012 to Sep 2016

- \* Domain: IBM Practice
- \* Clients: Bene-fit US, Kuwait Oil Company (KOC) Kuwait, Burlington Northern Santa Fe (BNSF) US, DSC Logistics-Supply Chain Management Company US
- \* Technologies: Liferay DXP, JDK8, JSR286, PostgreSQL9.4, Amazon Web Services, Apache Webserver 2.4, Nexus, Jenkins, Nginx, IBM Intelligent Operations Center(IOC) v1.6.0.2, IBM Integrated Information Core(IIC) v1.5, IBM Integration Bus v10, Wensphere Portal server v10, Websphere Application server v10, DB2v10, IBM Connections 5.x, IBM Http Server (IHS), MSAD, RAD 8.5.
- \* Introduced IBMIICv1.5 infrastructure and management tools to client to create and manage virtual server computing environment.
- \* Developed, updated and organized Liferay Portal based, PostgreSQL databases to handle customer and Health-domain data.
- \* Administered, supported and monitored databases by proactively resolving database issues and maintaining servers.
- \* Identified and implemented strategic plans based on accurate readings of specifications and solid collaboration with project leadership.
- \* Enhanced availability of infrastructure through enterprise-wide planning, thorough testing, efficient implementation and comprehensive support.
- \* Implemented corrective plans of action for network performance issues including availability, utilization, and latency.
- \* Facilitated smooth network operations for 150 on-site users, and total of 600 users across 3 locations for \$3.6 million catalog company.
- \* Performed system maintenance and upgrades, including patches, service packs, hot fixes and new security configurations.
- \* Managed data backups and disaster recovery operations for 500-person company.
- \* Wrote and maintained technical and functional specifications to document database intentions and requirements.
- \* Guided and directed third-party inspectors through project construction, commissioning and closeout.
- \* Collaborated with management, technical crew members and fellow supervisors to organize efficient site operations and achieve demanding schedule targets.
- \* Handled all issues with relative ease by implementing best practices and applying critical thinking skills to find best solutions.
- Lovely Professional University as Assistant Professor, Consultant Jul 2010 to Dec 2011
- IIITM Gwalior as Research Scholar Aug 2008 to Jun 2010
- Nelito Systems as Consultant Jan 2007 to Apr 2008

^ Back to Top

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2006

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Indian Institute of Information Technology and Management (ABV-IIITM), Gwalior in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Azure Administrator Associate AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

^ Back to Top

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
AWS Architect		2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JAVA	JDK8	2020	8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
LIFERAY	DXP	2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Kubernetes	v1.17	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Apache Tomcat	V9.x	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

#### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			

Hindi	Expert
Telugu	Expert

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

# **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.